Alex Ross

awhr95@gmail.com +44 (0) 788 200 8460 linkedin.com/in/alex-ross95 github.com/awhr95

SKILLS

JavaScript, Node.js, SCSS, Express, SQL, MySQL, Knex, Pvthon

PROFILE

I have spent the last 6 years working in successful startups (pre-seed to Series B) in commercial roles. I have been highly successful at delivering large scale complex technology implementations utilising my skills in collaboration, communication & domain expertise in legal technology and cyber security. I have loved working with disruptive technologies and this led me to building out my own technical skill set in order to transition to software development. After 12 months of self directed learning. the BrainStation bootcamp has been a fantastic launching point into my first software engineering role, bringing with me my years of commercial experience.

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

Nov 2023 - Feb 2023, London

Newcastle University | Bachelors in Physical Geography

Sept 2011 - 2016, Newcastle, UK

Grade (2.1)

Dissertation title "Smart Cities: How aware are users of Smart Initiatives of the relative negative & positive aspects of technologically driven change within the Newcastle Metro Service?"

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Internship | Risk Ledger

August - Sept 2023, London

- Supported the delivery of an updated Risk Calculation tool based on customer feedback
- Participated in Daily Stand-Up & shadowed senior team members

Account Executive | Risk Ledger

May 2021 - August 2023, London,

- The first Account Executive at Risk Ledger. Exceeding targets I delivered £650k in total contract value (closing 20+ customers)
- I was valued for my consultative approach, demonstrating my strong communication skills. Collaborating with multiple teams and stakeholders (internally & externally)
- Delivering large scale projects & contracts working from the C-level down - Customer include NHS England, Southern Water, Times Higher Education,

Senior Legal Product Expert | Luminance

JAN 2017 - May 2021, London

- Team Leader of four Legal Product Experts, sourcing new customers & working with 20-25 accounts, from global top 100 law firms to ftse100 organizations
- Seconded to the Luminance New York office for 3 months
- Ran projects in conjunction with clients for example the most successful project I worked on was with <u>Bird & Bird</u>. I collaborated with the Luminance development team and end users to ensure the delivery of the largest 'project' Luminance had seen with functionality that was at that time in beta testing.
- Spoke on the subject of AI in Law at conferences internationally (Legal Geek NY, Legal Geek London, LegalTech Warsaw,)

PROJECTS

Project Support | Risk Calculation Feature

Sept 2023, Risk Ledger

I supported the lead developer in scoping a new feature to Risk Ledger Risk Calculation feature **Tech used:** Golang, SQL and Notion for the project proposal.

Lead Developer | Capstone project - NList

Jan-Feb 2023, Brainstation

I built and deployed NList, the 'Airbnb' of volunteering. An app to support volunteers and charities connect, encourage more volunteering and aid organizations in finding volunteers. Built across 2 weeks. <u>Github link</u>

Tech used: Javascript, React, SASS, Node.js, Express, Knex/SQL, MySQL, Figma, Jira

Developer | Industry project - Deliveroo

Jan 2023, Brainstation & Deliveroo

Working in a cross collaboration 'industry project' with the UX team at brainstation we delivered a working prototype of new "Gifting Feature" - Design and research phase followed by delegation and task delivery. We built and demonstrated a working app within 24hr.. Github Link

Tech used: Javascript, React, SASS, Node.js, Express, Figma